Guide to the Butte (Mont.) Tombstone Company Records 1926-1966
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Butte (Mont.) Tombstone Company Records
1926-1966
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 164
Butte (Mont.) Tombstone Company
14.0 linear feet
The collection contains financial records including volumes for price lists, engraver's records, outside and Butte shipping slips from 1926 to 1966.
Historical Note
Albert Mooney founded the Butte Tombstone Company in 1902 under the parent company of Cory Operations. He operated the business until his death in 1965. During the early 1900s until after World War II, Cory Operations controlled all aspects of tombstone manufacturing, from extraction of the granite to sale of the finished product. After the war, it became more cost-effective to buy the granite from extraction companies. Since marble cracked in the wet and cold weather of Montana, he made tombstones out of more durable granite. After Mooney's death, the Choquette family bought the company and operated it until 1983, when they sold it to Glenn Johnson. Johnson bought the company in name only, operating it under his family's company, Trevillion Johnson Memorials, which was started by Johnson's great-grandfather, Edwin Walker, in 1889. The Butte Tombstone Company went out of business in 1990.
The collection contains financial records including volumes for price lists, engraver's records, outside and Butte shipping slips from 1926 to 1966.
The collection is arranged in a single series.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
This collection was in the possession of Paul McLeod prior to donation to the K. Ross Toole Archives.
Gift of Glenn Johnson, 1990.
The Montana Historical Society also holds 18 linear feet of Butte Tombstone Company records from 1903-1967.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Cory Operations
Business records--Montana
Burial--Montana; Sepulchral monuments--Montana
Butte (Mont.)--Commerce; Montana--Commerce
Mooney, Albert S.
Montana
- Financial Records, 1926-1966; Series I; 14.0 linear feet
  The series contains volumes of price list records, engraver's records, outside shipping slips (for items shipped outside Butte), and Butte shipping slips (for items shipped within Butte). The price lists detail the description of the headstone, including the dimensions and the price that was charged to the buyer. The volumes also include the name of the purchaser, the date that the stone was processed and the time spent working on it. The volumes are arranged alphabetically by the company's sizing system. The series also contains the engraver's records which correspond to the records kept in the price list volumes.
  The volumes are organized by the job number of the stone. Outside shipping slips are organized by the city in which the completed stone was sent, such as Anaconda, Deer Lodge, Dillon, Helena, Idaho, and other outside states. The records are organized by work number and include the name of the deceased with the birth and death dates, the purchaser of the stone, and the date when the order was paid in full. The shipper's name and address and shipment date, and a detailed description of the stone are also in the outside shipping slips. The Butte shipping slips contain the same information on them as in the outside shipping slips except the name of the cemetery is included. The volumes are arranged by name of cemetery, including Holy Cross, Mountain View, Mountain Moriah, St. Patrick, and UG Weeks.
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  - Price Lists, 1926 (Box-volume 1/1)
  - Engraver's Records, 1926 (Box-volume 1/2)
  - Engraver's Records, 1926 (Box-volume 1/3)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1926 (Box-volume 1/4)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1926 (Box-volume 1/5)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1926 (Box-volume 1/6)
  - Price Lists, 1927 (Box-volume 2/7)
  - Engraver's Records, 1927 (Box-volume 2/8)
  - Engraver's Records, 1927 (Box-volume 2/9)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1927 (Box-volume 2/10)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1927 (Box-volume 2/11)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1927 (Box-volume 2/12)
  - Price Lists, 1928 (Box-volume 3/13)
  - Engraver's Records, 1928 (Box-volume 3/14)
  - Engraver's Records, 1928 (Box-volume 3/15)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1928 (Box-volume 3/16)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1928 (Box-volume 3/17)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1928 (Box-volume 3/18)
  - Price Lists, 1929 (Box-volume 4/19)
  - Engraver's Records, 1929 (Box-volume 4/20)
  - Engraver's Records, 1929 (Box-volume 4/21)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1929 (Box-volume 4/22)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1929 (Box-volume 4/23)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1929 (Box-volume 4/24)
  - Price Lists, 1930 (Box-volume 5/25)
  - Engraver's Records, 1930 (Box-volume 5/26)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1930 (Box-volume 5/27)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1930 (Box-volume 5/28)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1930 (Box-volume 5/29)
  - Price Lists, 1931 (Box-volume 5/30)
  - Engraver's Records, 1931 (Box-volume 6/31)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1931 (Box-volume 6/32)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1931 (Box-volume 6/33)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1931 (Box-volume 6/34)
  - Price Lists, 1932 (Box-volume 6/35)
  - Engraver's Records, 1932 (Box-volume 6/36)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1932 (Box-volume 6/37)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1932 (Box-volume 7/38)
  - Price Lists, 1933 (Box-volume 7/39)
  - Engraver's Records, 1933 (Box-volume 7/40)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1933 (Box-volume 7/41)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1933 (Box-volume 7/42)
  - Price Lists, 1934 (Box-volume 7/43)
  - Engraver's Records, 1934 (Box-volume 7/44)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1934 (Box-volume 7/45)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1934 (Box-volume 8/46)
  - Price Lists, 1935 (Box-volume 8/47)
  - Engraver's Records, 1935 (Box-volume 8/48)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1935 (Box-volume 8/48)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1935 (Box-volume 8/49)
  - Price Lists, 1936 (Box-volume 8/50)
  - Engraver's Records, 1936 (Box-volume 9/51)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1936 (Box-volume 9/52)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1936 (Box-volume 9/53)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1936 (Box-volume 9/54)
  - Price Lists, 1937 (Box-volume 9/55)
  - Engraver's Records, 1937 (Box-volume 9/56)
  - Engraver's Records, 1937 (Box-volume 10/57)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1937 (Box-volume 10/58)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1937 (Box-volume 10/59)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1937 (Box-volume 10/60)
  - Price Lists, 1938 (Box-volume 10/61)
  - Engraver's Records, 1938 (Box-volume 10/62)
  - Engraver's Records, 1938 (Box-volume 11/63)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1938 (Box-volume 11/64)
  - Butte Shipping Records, 1938 (Box-volume 11/65)
  - Price Lists, 1939 (Box-volume 11/66)
  - Engraver's Records, 1939 (Box-volume 11/67)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1939 (Box-volume 11/68)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1939 (Box-volume 12/69)
  - Price Lists, 1940 (Box-volume 12/70)
  - Engraver's Records, 1940 (Box-volume 12/71)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1940 (Box-volume 12/72)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1940 (Box-volume 12/73)
  - Engraver's Records, 1941 (Box-volume 12/74a)
  - Price Lists, 1941 (Box-volume 12/74b)
  - Outside Shipping Records, 1941 (Box-volume 13/75)
  - Butte Shipping Records, 1941 (Box-volume 13/76)
  - Price Lists, 1942 (Box-volume 13/77)
  - Engraver's Records, 1942 (Box-volume 13/78)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1942 (Box-volume 13/79)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1942 (Box-volume 13/80)
  - Engraver's Records, 1943 (Box-volume 14/81)
  - Price Lists, 1943 (Box-volume 14/82)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1943 (Box-volume 14/83)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1943 (Box-volume 14/84)
  - Price Lists, 1944 (Box-volume 14/85)
  - Price Lists, 1944 (Box-volume 14/86)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1944 (Box-volume 15/87)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1944 (Box-volume 15/88)
  - Price Lists, 1945 (Box-volume 15/89)
  - Price Lists, 1945 (Box-volume 15/90)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1945 (Box-volume 15/91)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1945 (Box-volume 15/92)
  - Price Lists, 1946 (Box-volume 16/93)
  - Price Lists, 1946 (Box-volume 16/94)
  - Price Lists, 1946 (Box-volume 16/95)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1946 (Box-volume 16/96)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1946 (Box-volume 16/97)
  - Price Lists, 1947 (Box-volume 16/98a)
  - Price Lists, 1947 (Box-volume 16/98b)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1947 (Box-volume 17/99)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1947 (Box-volume 17/100)
  - Price Lists, 1948 (Box-volume 17/101)
  - Price Lists, 1948 (Box-volume 17/102)
  - Price Lists, 1948 (Box-volume 17/103)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1948 (Box-volume 17/104)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1948 (Box-volume 17/105)
  - Price Lists, 1949 (Box-volume 18/106)
  - Price Lists, 1949 (Box-volume 18/107)
  - Price Lists, 1949 (Box-volume 18/108)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1949 (Box-volume 18/109)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1949 (Box-volume 18/110)
  - Price Lists, 1950 (Box-volume 18/111)
  - Price Lists, 1950 (Box-volume 18/112)
  - Price Lists, 1950 (Box-volume 19/113)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1950 (Box-volume 19/114)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1950 (Box-volume 19/115)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1950 (Box-volume 19/116)
  - Price Lists, 1951 (Box-volume 19/117)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1951 (Box-volume 19/118)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1951 (Box-volume 19/119)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1951 (Box-volume 19/120)
  - Price Lists, 1951 (Box-volume 20/121)
  - Price Lists, 1952 (Box-volume 20/122)
  - Price Lists, 1952 (Box-volume 20/123)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1952 (Box-volume 20/124a)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1952 (Box-volume 20/124b)
  - Price Lists, 1953 (Box-volume 20/125)
  - Price Lists, 1953 (Box-volume 20/126)
  - Price Lists, 1953 (Box-volume 20/127)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1953 (Box-volume 21/128)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1953 (Box-volume 21/129)
  - Price Lists, 1954 (Box-volume 21/130)
  - Price Lists, 1954 (Box-volume 21/131)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1954 (Box-volume 21/132)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1954 (Box-volume 21/133)
  - Price Lists, 1954 (Box-volume 22/134)
  - Price Lists, 1955 (Box-volume 22/135)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1955 (Box-volume 22/136)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1955 (Box-volume 22/137)
  - Price Lists, 1955 (Box-volume 22/138)
  - Price Lists, 1955 (Box-volume 22/139)
  - Price Lists, 1956 (Box-volume 22/140)
  - Price Lists, 1956 (Box-volume 22/141)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1956 (Box-volume 23/142)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1956 (Box-volume 23/143)
  - Price Lists, 1957 (Box-volume 23/144a)
  - Price Lists, 1957 (Box-volume 23/144b)
  - Price Lists, 1957 (Box-volume 23/145)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1957 (Box-volume 23/146)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1957 (Box-volume 23/147)
  - Price Lists, 1958 (Box-volume 24/148)
  - Price Lists, 1958 (Box-volume 24/149)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1958 (Box-volume 24/150)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1958 (Box-volume 24/151)
  - Price Lists, 1959 (Box-volume 24/152)
  - Price Lists, 1959 (Box-volume 24/153)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1959 (Box-volume 24/154)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1959 (Box-volume 25/155)
  - Price Lists, 1960 (Box-volume 25/156)
  - Price Lists, 1960 (Box-volume 25/157)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1960 (Box-volume 25/158)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1960 (Box-volume 25/159)
  - Price Lists, 1961 (Box-volume 25/160)
  - Price Lists, 1961 (Box-volume 26/161)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1961 (Box-volume 26/162)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1961 (Box-volume 26/163)
  - Price Lists, 1962 (Box-volume 26/164)
  - Price Lists, 1962 (Box-volume 26/165)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1962 (Box-volume 26/166)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1962 (Box-volume 26/167)
  - Price Lists, 1963 (Box-volume 27/168)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1963 (Box-volume 27/169)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1963 (Box-volume 27/170)
  - Price Lists, 1964 (Box-volume 27/171)
  - Price Lists, 1964 (Box-volume 27/172)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1964 (Box-volume 27/173)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1964 (Box-volume 27/174)
  - Price Lists, 1965 (Box-volume 28/175)
  - Price Lists, 1965 (Box-volume 28/176)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1965 (Box-volume 28/177)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1965 (Box-volume 28/178)
  - Price Lists, 1966 (Box-volume 28/179)
  - Price Lists, 1966 (Box-volume 28/180)
  - Outside Shipping Slips, 1966 (Box-volume 28/181)
  - Butte Shipping Slips, 1966 (Box-volume 28/182)